directionsmag.com 2003-12-04

# Directions Magazine Web Site Privacy Statement - Directions Magazine

Directions Magazine Web Site Privacy Statement|   
---|---  
Directions Magazine respects the privacy of every individual who visits our Web sites. This Privacy Statement outlines the information we collect via our various Web sites and how we use that information. 

#### Personally Identifiable Information

Directions Magazine collects personally identifiable information such as your name, address, telephone number, or E-mail address **only** if you provide that information to us voluntarily such as survey information and/or site registrations. 

The voluntary information we collect is used for internal review and to notify visitors about updates to our Web site. Even though we may share aggregate data with our readers and advertisers, **we will not share individual information with others.** We also run contests on our site in which we ask visitors for contact information (like their e-mail address) for notification of winners. 

We use E-mail links located on various pages to allow you to contact us directly with any questions or comments you may have. We read every message sent in and try to reply promptly to every one. This information is used to respond directly to your questions or comments. We may also file your comments to improve the site and program, or review and discard the information. Your comments may be shared with third parties only for the purpose of getting answers to your questions. 

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. 

Otherwise, Directions Magazine generally will not disclose your personally identifiable information unless required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (1) conform to the edicts of the law; (2) protect and defend the rights or property of Directions Magazine. 

#### Information Collected Automatically

We automatically log information such as your domain name (ex. _mindspring.com_ ), the type if Internet browser you use, the operating system you use. We also may log what pages are viewed. This information is used **only** for internal review to help us improve the content of our magazine. The information is not shared with any other company or used by Directions Magazine to contact clients.

#### Cookies

Some of our Web sites store some information on your computer in the form of a "cookie." A cookie is a small data file that certain Web sites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie file contains information such as a user ID that the site uses to track the pages you have visited. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie cannot read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. These are used to store information you provide to prevent you from having to enter that same information repeatedly, to keep track of who posted uploads in case there are problems, to deter multiple votes on issues from the same person, and to help us collect minimal information to maintain and improve our site.

With most Internet browsers, you can erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block all cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Please refer to your browser instructions or help screen to learn more about these functions.

#### Links to Other Web sites

The Directions Magazine site offers links to hundreds of GIS-related Web sites. Directions Magazine assumes no responsibility for the information practices of these sites, and these links do not imply affiliation or endorsement of the linked sites. 

#### Removing Your Information from Our Databases

If you do not wish to receive E-mail notifications about Directions Magazine, please let us know by sending E-mail to us at [website@directionsmag.com](mailto:website@directionsmag.com) and specifying us that you do not want to receive these notifications. Please provide us with your exact name and address, and if possible a reason why you would like removed from these mailing. We will use reasonable efforts to delete this information from our existing files.

Directions Magazine does not intentionally collect personally identifiable information such as name, address, telephone number, or E-mail address from children. However, users of any age can download our free software, participate in surveys or wish lists which require a name and E-mail address.

If a child has provided us with personally identifiable information and the parent or guardian of that child would like that information deleted from our records, the parent or guardian should contact us at [website@directionsmag.com](mailto:website@directionsmag.com). We will use reasonable efforts to delete the child's information from our existing files.
